netmeds.com 2018-09-07

# Privacy Policy - Netmeds.com

Welcome to www.netmeds.com ("Netmeds.com", "Netmeds", "Website", "Pharmacy", or "we"). This website ownwed and operated by Netmeds Marketplace Limited,whose registered office is in Chennai,India

 **1\. Absolute Confidentiality**

1.1 www.netmeds.com (also referred to as "Netmeds.com" or "Website" or "We") is totally committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring the security of any personal information received from you ("Customer"). At Netmeds.com, the confidentiality of our Customers is a top priority. We strictly adhere to the requirements of the data protection law established in India and this Privacy Policy is published in accordance with:

  * Section 43 A of the Information Technology Act, 2000;
  * Regulation 4 of the Information Technology (Reasonable Security Practices and Procedures and Sensitive Personal Information) Rules, 2011 (the "SPI Rules"); and
  * Regulation 3(1) of the Information Technology (Intermediaries Guidelines) Rules, 2011.

1.2 The purpose of this privacy policy statement is to explain to you what personal information We collect from your visit(s) to our Website, and how We protect the information that you provide to us when you use our Website. You can be assured that Netmeds.com will use such information sensibly and carefully, and only in accordance with this privacy statement. We maintain compliance with the highest standards of website privacy, so our visitors/Customers can securely place orders on our Website. This Privacy Policy is effective from 21/05/2015. Any information that you provide to Netmeds.com is subject to our Privacy Policy.

**2\. Your Consent**

2.1 By accessing this Website and whenever you submit any information to Netmeds.com, or use products and services offered by our Website, you agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. Please read below carefully the entire Privacy Policy before using Netmeds.com website: 

2.2 As part of providing our Services to you, We may need to send routine communications to you, such as order transaction emails and other administrative messages through email and notifications posted on the Website or through other means available, including text and other forms of messaging. Though we prefer to communicate with our Customers via email, as may be deemed necessary, you agree to receive our phone calls, related to your orders/request on Netmeds.com. 

2.3 When you sign up to receive our enewsletters, We may periodically send emails about new products, special offers or other information, which you may find it interesting and beneficial as well. If you do not wish to receive promotional information from us, you can, at any time, choose to opt out of receiving Netmeds promotional enewsletters. To unsubscribe from our enewsletters, you can follow the directions included at the enewsletter. 

2.4 You must ensure to provide us with the correct or up-to-date Personal Information. This will allow us to contact you for further correspondences with respect to your order at Netmeds.com. We are not responsible for any inaccurate information you provide to us, which may affect your shopping experience on our website. 

2.5 If, at any time, you want to access, update, modify or eliminate any of your account information at Netmeds.com, you may do so by clicking "Your Account", and then review/change your sensitive personal information as you want it to be. 

2.6 Netmeds.com may, in future, request other optional information from you in order to customise the Website to deliver personalised service to our Customers.

**3\. What Information We Collect About You**

3.1 We do not automatically collect your personally identifiable information. However, you might provide us with your personal and demographic information – including your name, gender, age, address, phone number, email address and your medical prescription(s) – in the following ways: 

  * As a New Customer, when you register/create an account, place your order, or upload your medical prescription at Netmeds.com;
  * As an Existing Customer, when you update your existing profile on Netmeds.com;
  * When you sign up for enewsletters at Netmeds.com;
  * When you use Refer & Earn programme, Ask Our Pharmacist service, Contact Us or submit your Testimonials at Netmeds.com.

3.2 During your visit to our Website, We may automatically receive technical information about your computer/device, including your IP address, your computer operating system, time-zone, browser type and browser plug-in details, due to the communication protocol settings on the Internet. 

3.3 When you browse our Website, We may also collect information regarding the pages you viewed, the web addresses from which you arrive or click through to, time spent on certain pages, download errors and page response times. All these information help us analyse Customers' trends and preferences, and thus assist us in improving our service.

**4\. How We Use the Information Collected from You**

4.1 We will collect and retain your personally identifiable information only to the extent that it is necessary to fulfil our services to you. Any Personal information submitted by you to the Website or collected by us will be used ONLY for the purposes mentioned below: 

4.1.1 To carry out our obligations arising from your requests for our products and services; 

4.1.2 To improve our Website's functionality, and to customise your future shopping experience with us; 

4.1.3 To make sure that our Website content is presented in the manner that is most effective for you; 

4.1.4 To communicate with you about any changes to our services; 

4.1.5 To verify your identity and perform checks to prevent fraud.

**5\. With Whom We Share Your Information**

5.1 We do not sell, rent or exchange your any personally identifiable information that you provide to us through this Website with any third party for commercial reasons. However, We engage trusted online payment service partners to perform payment processing and authorisation services (for net banking or credit/debit card validation). Through your use of the Netmeds.com Services, you consent to our collection and transfer of your information to our payment service partner websites.

5.2 As with any business, it is possible that as our business develops, we might sell or buy other businesses or assets. In such transactions, User/Customer information is typically one of the transferred business assets. Accordingly, in the event that Netmeds.com, or substantially all of our assets, is acquired by a third party, such information may be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. Under such circumstances, Netmeds.com would, to the extent possible, require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Netmeds.com may continue to process your personal information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**6\. Who Has Access to Your Information**

Your personally identifiable information can be accessed only on a need-to-know basis by certain Netmeds.com employees who are designated to carry out your requested activity, and all such employees are bound to strict confidentiality obligations.

**7\. How We Use Cookies**

7.1 "Cookies" are small pieces of information placed by a website onto your computer's hard drive. Cookies do not collect any sensitive personal information from you. We use cookies to analyse data about our web page traffic, which helps us save your preferences for your future visits. This allows us to customise our website according to your interests, which will enable us to deliver a more personalised service to our customers. You may choose to accept or decline cookies. Please be aware that by declining cookies you may be unable to use our website to its fullest capability.

**8\. Security Policy**

We guarantee that all your personal information with us is secure. Netmeds.com takes careful precaution to protect our Customers' personal information from unauthorised access, improper use or disclosure or unauthorised modification. To prevent unauthorised access, we have put in place the latest industry-standard security technology and procedures to safeguard the information we collect online. Your personal information is encrypted and is protected with 256-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts all information you input. We store your personally identifiable information on the computer servers placed in a secure environment. Even though we have taken significant steps to protect your personally identifiable information, no company, including our Website, can fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information.

**9\. Maintain Confidentiality of Your Prescription**

We understand the confidential nature of the prescription you provide us to process your medication order and we treat your prescription as a protected information.

**10\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time by updating this page, and so we urge you to review it periodically to ensure that you agree with any such changes that we make. We will make best efforts to inform you of any important amendments by e-mail, message on the Website or notification in Your Account. However, it is your responsibility to check the Policy regularly to ensure that you agree with it and your continued use of the Website will be deemed to be your acceptance of any changes that we make. 

Last updated Date: 27/03/2018.

**11\. Contact Information**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact Ramesh Kumar ([legal@netmeds.com](mailto:legal@netmeds.com)) or our customer service at [cs@netmeds.com](mailto:cs@netmeds.com) or call 72007-12345.

Excellence, Expertise and  
Experience in Pharma since 1914
